<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Workshops on RFUN-ZOPE</title>
    <link>/categories/workshops/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Workshops on RFUN-ZOPE</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/workshops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Workshop video recordings (2021)</title>
      <link>/blog/spring-videos-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/spring-videos-2021/</guid>
      <description>Now streaming: All spring 2021 Rfun workshop videos.
Hundreds of you signed-up and attended our workshops last semester. Now, we are pleased to present the Spring 2021 Rfun workshop series on video. As always, the content for each workshop is available for sharing via CC BY-NC license (i.e. Attribution, Non-Commercial.) We encourage you to share the videos, the data, and the code.
Within the description of each video (and/or often within the video) you&amp;rsquo;ll find links to the code and data stored on GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring 2021 Workshops</title>
      <link>/blog/spring-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/spring-2021/</guid>
      <description>Winter/Spring 2021 brings new Rfun workshops. Due to COVID The Center for Data &amp;amp; Visualization Sciences will continue our remote workshop series via Zoom. Please find the registration links below.
If you missed anything last fall, you can find links to past workshop resources including streaming video and shareable code. Beyond Rfun, check out the whole array of CDVS workshop resources. Register and join us.
   Title Date Registration     R for data science: getting started, EDA, data wrangling 28_Jan  https://duke.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring 2021: case studies</title>
      <link>/blog/spring-case-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/spring-case-studies/</guid>
      <description>RStudio is an interface that assists your reproducible workflows. Explore how the Tidyverse environment is more than statistics. These hands-on concepts explore practical features of data gathering and data manipulation. Go beyond the rudimentary to expand your ideas of analysis.
In the spring of 2021, we will explore the following as case studies…
Register    Title Date Registration     Public datasets in Google BigQuery using DBplyr 25_Feb  https://duke.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fall 2019 Rfun Workshops</title>
      <link>/blog/fall-2019-rfun/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/fall-2019-rfun/</guid>
      <description>We invite you to join us for an informative semester of workshops about R, RStudio, and the Tidyverse. Our Rfun workshops provide a gentle hands-on introduction to a powerful &amp;ldquo;data first&amp;rdquo; programming language, R. The R ecosystem is tweaked for research through data analysis and will grow gracefully with your needs. Best of all, R anticipates reproducibility as a foundational asset of your research workflow. We look forward to showing you how R can work for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fall 2018 Rfun Review</title>
      <link>/blog/fall-2018-rfun-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/fall-2018-rfun-review/</guid>
      <description>Below please find a brief list of workshop titles offered through the Fall of 2018. Each title will link to further information about the workshop including a streamable recording of the workshop (if available), shareable code, presentation slide decks, and any further information.
Currently, the Data &amp;amp; Visualization Services Department is actively organizing our Spring 2019 workshop series &amp;ndash; including the Rfun subseries. Stay tuned to our channels (DVS list | Rfun list | DVS Twitter) or websites (DVS | Rfun) for details on the upcoming workshop schedule.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fall 2018 Rfun Workshops</title>
      <link>/blog/fall-2018-rfun-workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/fall-2018-rfun-workshops/</guid>
      <description>The Rfun series welcomes you back to the Duke University campus and we invite you to join us for an informative semester of workshops about R using RStudio and the Tidyverse. These workshops will provide you with a gentle hands-on introduction to a most powerful data science toolkit. Attend one or attend them all.
The cost is free and registration is for in-person attendance only. Fortunately the resources are shareable. You can find links to previous workshop resources (code, video, github) on this very website: https://rfun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to R -- Workshop</title>
      <link>/blog/introduction-to-r-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/introduction-to-r-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Joel Herndon and I regularly present sections of the Intro to R Workshop hosted by the Data and Visualization Services Department.
The workshops &amp;ndash; official entitled Intro to R: Data Transformations, Data Structures, and the Tidyverse &amp;ndash; is a the two-hour, hands-on session designed to provide a gentle introduction to the basics of the Tidyverse data science approach to the R statistical programming language. We use the RStudio development environment. Attendees learn about managing R projects, data types, variable assignments, data wrangling and visualization, and mapping using a focused approach to modern data science known as the tidyverse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualization in R using ggplot2</title>
      <link>/blog/visualization-in-r-using-ggplot2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/visualization-in-r-using-ggplot2/</guid>
      <description>Angela Zoss (DVS Staff page) presents a visualization workshop hosted by the Data and Visualization Services Department.
The workshops, officially entitled Visualization in R using ggplot2, is a two-hour, hands-on learning session designed to introduce the ggplot2 package, a programming library within the R programming language. The ggplot2 library for R creates clear and well-designed visualizations that plays well with other tidyverse packages.
Data science skills are increasingly important for research and industry projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reproducibility: Version Control, Git, and RStudio</title>
      <link>/blog/reproducibility-version-control-git-and-rstudio/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/reproducibility-version-control-git-and-rstudio/</guid>
      <description>Sophia Lafferty-Hess (DVS Staff page), Jen Darragh (DVS Staff page), and I presented a Reproducibility workshop hosted by the Data and Visualization Services Department and cross-listed with the Responsible Conduct of Research (RCR) training efforts.
The workshops, officially entitled Reproducibility: RStudio and Git is a hands-on response to the importance of reproducibility, replication, and transparency in the research endeavor. General data management strategies are introduced to assist researchers in their efforts towards increased research reproducibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter/Spring 2018 R Workshops:  Summary Review</title>
      <link>/blog/winter-spring-2018-r-workshops-summary-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/winter-spring-2018-r-workshops-summary-review/</guid>
      <description>This past spring the Data &amp;amp; Visualization Services Department hosted a six-part workshop series on the R programming language. Our goals for the workshop series is to introduce R as a language for modern data manipulation. We do this by highlighting a basic set of packages that enable functional and practical data science. We approach R using the free RStudio IDE, an intent to make reproducible literate code, and a bias towards the tidyverse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidyverse Workshops coming in January</title>
      <link>/blog/tidyverse-workshops-coming-in-january/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/tidyverse-workshops-coming-in-january/</guid>
      <description>This winter the Data &amp;amp; Visualization Services Department will once again host a workshop series on the R programming language. Our spring offering is modeled on our well received R we having fun yet‽ (Rfun) fall workshop series. The four-part series will introduce R as a language for modern data manipulation by highlighting a set of tidyverse packages that enable functional data science. We will approach R using the free RStudio IDE, an intent to make reproducible literate code, and a bias towards the tidyverse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fall 2017 R Workshops: Summary Review</title>
      <link>/blog/fall-2017-r-workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/fall-2017-r-workshops/</guid>
      <description>This fall the Data &amp;amp; Visualization Services Department hosted a five-part workshop series on the R programming language. Our goal: introduce R as a language for modern data manipulation by highlighting a basic set of packages that enable functional and practical data science. To that end, we approach R using the free RStudio IDE, an intent to make reproducible literate code, and a bias towards the tidyverse. We believe this tool-set provides a context that enables and reinforces workflows, analysis and reporting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing Interactive Websites with R and Shiny -- Workshop, Fall 2017</title>
      <link>/blog/developing-interactive-websites-with-r-and-shiny-workshop-fall-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/developing-interactive-websites-with-r-and-shiny-workshop-fall-2017/</guid>
      <description>On October 2nd, Joel Herndon presented a workshop on Shiny hosted by the Data and Visualization Services Department: Developing Interactive Websites with R and Shiny.
Learn how to leverage your knowledge of R and R Markdown to create compelling, interactive website and interactive documents using the Shiny web application framework. Shiny makes it easy to transition from desktop based analysis and visualizations to interactive websites without having to learn HTML, CSS, and javascript.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping with R -- Workshop, Fall 2017</title>
      <link>/blog/mapping-with-r-workshop-fall-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/mapping-with-r-workshop-fall-2017/</guid>
      <description>On October 2nd, I presented a Mapping with R workshop hosted by the Data and Visualization Services Department.
R has become a popular and reproducible option for supporting spatial and statistical analysis. This hands-on workshop will demonstrate how to plot x/y coordinates using leaflet; how to generate thematic choropleths with US Census and other federal data (using tmap and tidycensus); import, view and produce shapefiles; and create leaflet maps for viewing on the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualization in R using ggplot2 -- Workshop, Fall 2017</title>
      <link>/blog/visualization-in-r-using-ggplot2-workshop-fall-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/visualization-in-r-using-ggplot2-workshop-fall-2017/</guid>
      <description>On September 25, 2017 Angela Zoss (DVS Staff page) presented a visualization workshop hosted by the Data and Visualization Services Department.
The workshops, officially entitled Visualization in R using ggplot2, is a two-hour, hands-on learning session designed to introduce the ggplot2 package, a programming library within the R programming language. The ggplot2 library for R creates clear and well-designed visualizations that plays well with other tidyverse packages.
Data science skills are increasingly important for research and industry projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reproducibility: Data Management, Git, and RStudio -- Workshop, Fall 2017</title>
      <link>/blog/reproducibility-data-management-git-and-rstudio-workshop-fall-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/reproducibility-data-management-git-and-rstudio-workshop-fall-2017/</guid>
      <description>On September 18, 2017 Sophia Lafferty-Hess (DVS Staff page), Jen Darragh (DVS Staff page), and I presented a Reproducibility workshop hosted by the Data and Visualization Services Department and cross-listed with the Responsible Conduct of Research (RCR) training efforts.
The workshops, officially entitled Reproducibility: Data Management, Git, and RStudio is a two-hour, hands-on response to a growing focus on the importance of reproducibility, replication, and transparency in the research endeavor. General data management strategies are introduced to assist researchers in their efforts towards increased research reproducibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fall 2017 RFUN Workshops</title>
      <link>/blog/fall-2017-rfun-workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/fall-2017-rfun-workshops/</guid>
      <description>The RFun Series is BackIntroducing the Fall 2017 RFun Series. We’ve expanded and transformed the series to add more hands-on training opportunities. Links to registration are below.
Each R workshop will take place on a Monday, beginning in mid-September. Individual workshops will last two hours. The series will extend over four consecutive weeks followed by a brief respite. The fifth and final workshop will introduce Shiny, a package for developing interactive web visualizations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
