<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Resource-Links on RFUN-ZOPE</title>
    <link>/categories/resource-links/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Resource-Links on RFUN-ZOPE</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/resource-links/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fall 2019 Rfun Workshops</title>
      <link>/blog/fall-2019-rfun/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/fall-2019-rfun/</guid>
      <description>We invite you to join us for an informative semester of workshops about R, RStudio, and the Tidyverse. Our Rfun workshops provide a gentle hands-on introduction to a powerful &amp;ldquo;data first&amp;rdquo; programming language, R. The R ecosystem is tweaked for research through data analysis and will grow gracefully with your needs. Best of all, R anticipates reproducibility as a foundational asset of your research workflow. We look forward to showing you how R can work for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fall 2018 Rfun Review</title>
      <link>/blog/fall-2018-rfun-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/fall-2018-rfun-review/</guid>
      <description>Below please find a brief list of workshop titles offered through the Fall of 2018. Each title will link to further information about the workshop including a streamable recording of the workshop (if available), shareable code, presentation slide decks, and any further information.
Currently, the Data &amp;amp; Visualization Services Department is actively organizing our Spring 2019 workshop series &amp;ndash; including the Rfun subseries. Stay tuned to our channels (DVS list | Rfun list | DVS Twitter) or websites (DVS | Rfun) for details on the upcoming workshop schedule.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Data Sources for Regression Analysis</title>
      <link>/blog/data-sources-for-regression-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 09:24:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/data-sources-for-regression-analysis/</guid>
      <description>While Duke Libraries Data and Visualization Services provides a number of workshops on learning how to use R for data management, mapping, and visualization, we also receive a several questions each year from students searching for datasets to use in applied statistics courses at Duke. As others have noted, finding data sets that are engaging (for students) that provide a range of data types for analysis and don’t present too many data loading/cleaning challenges is harder than one might think.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fall 2018 Rfun Workshops</title>
      <link>/blog/fall-2018-rfun-workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/fall-2018-rfun-workshops/</guid>
      <description>The Rfun series welcomes you back to the Duke University campus and we invite you to join us for an informative semester of workshops about R using RStudio and the Tidyverse. These workshops will provide you with a gentle hands-on introduction to a most powerful data science toolkit. Attend one or attend them all.
The cost is free and registration is for in-person attendance only. Fortunately the resources are shareable. You can find links to previous workshop resources (code, video, github) on this very website: https://rfun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fall 2017 RFUN Workshops</title>
      <link>/blog/fall-2017-rfun-workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/fall-2017-rfun-workshops/</guid>
      <description>The RFun Series is BackIntroducing the Fall 2017 RFun Series. We’ve expanded and transformed the series to add more hands-on training opportunities. Links to registration are below.
Each R workshop will take place on a Monday, beginning in mid-September. Individual workshops will last two hours. The series will extend over four consecutive weeks followed by a brief respite. The fifth and final workshop will introduce Shiny, a package for developing interactive web visualizations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
